SOFTWARE ENGINEER Development experience: Pro

Development experience: Project Management and Java EE/Web Services

+20 years of Java development experience leading mid-size java projects specializing in web technology, middleware APIs and microservices.

Edgar A. Torres Email: eatorres2002@outlook.com

Professional Experience:

May 2022 - to date

Baja Technologies/Softeq - Epson

- Java Software Engineer I collaborated on two major applications for Epson's payments and procurements systems where custom workflows are implemented for purchase orders approvals, roles, reviews, invoicing and reporting. Successfully completed project tasks and resolved issues using the product digital process AMS Kanban board and development environments for microservices within the ecosystem. Conducted research and solved defects within Epayment and Eprocurement microservices ecosystems.
- I have participated within several Softeq internal applications of the Employee Management System such as profile and vacations.
- Tools used: SpringBoot, Maven, Gradle, IntelliJ IDEA, Angular, Git/Gitlab, Jira, confluence, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Docker, Postman, Swagger-UI, Amazon Workspaces VM.

Aug 2019 - to date

Al Mexico. (Non-profit)

- <u>Project Manager</u>. Al Mexico is a non-profit organization gathering Artificial intelligence talent for the Baja-Mexico
 region. I've been a volunteer project manager giving advice to teams as well as agile methodologies,
 contributing on training on scrum ceremonies, including other activities such as project proposals, cost
 estimation, events and conferences (meetups) planning.
- Tools used: Asana, Confluence, Zoom, Google Meet, OBS, Inkscape.

Sep 2020 - May 2022

Softtek - Metagenics (Healthcare)

- <u>Back-end developer</u> I participated within an application which provides services and support for healthcare
 practitioners, where patients' medical information is gathered by questionnaires for many healthcare areas and
 exam results data generated by either medical devices or health exams.
- Tools used: SpringBoot, Maven, STS, JEE, Git/Bitbucket, Jira, confluence, mongo DB, MySQL, postman.

Nov 2017 - Mar 2020

Softtek - 24 Hour Fitness. (Information Services/Fitness Center)

- <u>ESB Integration Developer:</u> Enterprise Service Bus (ESB) Integration developer for middleware Java Web-services (SOAP/REST) working within the Camunda BPM for 24 hour fitness products provided within sales & member inquiry systems. I implemented BPM processes & fixed reported defects among several layers as the Spring Layer, ESB layer, Data Services, and micro services for Dev & QA servers. ESB Profiling/Load testing reporting using Yourkit Profiler.
- Tools used: Eclipse, Git, Maven, JUnit/Mockito, Camunda BPM, JAX-WS/JAX-RS, XSLT, MySQL, Zuora Product Catalog, GridGain cache, readyAPI, postman, Jira, Bamboo, Jenkins, JMeter, Yourkit Profiler.

Apr 2017 - Sep 2017

Softtek - Preferred Employers Insurance. (Insurance)

- <u>Technical Leader/Developer</u>: The company provides workers' compensation insurance for a wide variety of
 industries. CompSupport is the company system supporting. Policy writing, Billing/Collections, Audits, Claims
 Administration, Finance and Reporting; it's built in a platform called Magic software which has a front-end
 interface and a back-end database management and programming platform known as Toolkit.
- Tools Used: Magic 9 Toolkit IDE, Eclipse IDE, GitHub, Maven, JUnit/Mockito, Crystal reports, MS SQL.

Nov 2014 - Mar 2017

Softtek - Sony Network Entertainment Network.

- <u>Technical Leader/Developer:</u> The Alternative Payment Methods (APM) & Mobile Operator Billing (MOB) are the new features for the SNEI Platform applications such as navigator-native, navigator-services middleware API and Global Registration CAM (GRC) including PlayStation Network and other Sony services.
- Implementation of multiple payment instruments (MPI) and 3DSecure for Visa/MasterCard Credit Cards validation within GRC. GRC enables the user to create and manage their accounts, wallet top-up, and devices; redeem vouchers and manage payment instruments (including Mobile Service Providers). Integration with Navigator-native is the first application tier on the network platform that most Sony devices interact with via a set of APIs; Clients of this application are: PS3, PSP, PS Vita, MediaGo, Sony Tablet, Xperia phones, etc.
- Tools Used: Eclipse/Spring Tool Suite IDE, Scrum/SAFe Methodology using Rally, Perforce P4, GitHub, Maven, Junit/EasyMock, Struts, ReviewBoard, Jenkins, Anthill, Grunt.

Nov 2012 - Apr 2014

Softtek - Sony Network Entertainment Network.

<u>Project Leader/Java Developer:</u> The Customer Management Tool (CMT) is a web application designed for ease
of use when assisting customers of Sony Entertainment Network (including PlayStation Network and
Music/Video Unlimited services). CMT enables the support user to locate/modify account information such as

billing, transactions, parental control, entitlements, subscriptions, chargebacks, credit cards, consoles, vouchers and promotions

- CCT is a Grails web application which manages country releases and configurations for production and non-production lines including its workflow approval process which involves user roles such as viewer, editor, approver and admin.
- I defined and implemented the Code Review Process as a Quick Hit Six Sigma project.
- Tools Used: Eclipse/Spring Tool Suite IDE, Groovy/Grails framework, Scrum Methodology using Rally, Perforce P4, Git/GitHub, Maven, Spock and GEB unit/functional testing tools, BackboneJS, CoffeeScript, Bootstrap,

Nov 2009 - Nov 2012

Softtek - Fender Musical Instruments

- Proiect Leader/Java Developer: I participated developing B2B J2EE e-commerce modules as promotions and warranty claims process implementation among other functionalities of the client dealers' systems.
- I defined a Quick-Hit Six Sigma project to improve OTD (On-time Delivery) and CPI (Cost performance index) project metrics.
- Tools used: Eclipse, JBoss, ATG e-commerce framework, MS-SQL 2005, Scrum, Rally Software, MongoDB, JSON, JQuery, prototypeJS, SVN.

Nov 2009 - Nov 2012

Softtek - Virgin Mobile USA

- QA CoE team member: I Designed performance Test Plans including load, stress and stability testing.
- I Developed test scripts to test Web/WAP APIs and Application servers. Defect tracking for applications functional testing. Automated Test Cases execution using JMeter and Selenium scripts.
- Tools used: JMeter, JUnit, JPerfMeter, Eclipse, NetBeans, JBoss, WebLogic 8.1, Tomcat 5.5, TheGrinder, Python, Selenium, Bugzilla, Testopia, HP Quality Center.

Feb 2009 - Mar 2009

Softtek - Kaplan University

- Java/Blackberry Developer: Participation in the development of the Java GUI for the Kaplan Blackberry RIM mobile student disbursements system.
- Tools used: Blackberry RIM Java SDK/Eclipse plug-in with Eclipse, Blackberry emulators (Pearl 8100 series, Curve 8300 series), Java, Tortoise SVN.

Nov 2008 - Jan 2009

Softtek - STC (Scientific Technologies Corporation)

- Java Developer: Development of base Web Services developed as a pilot project for the applications integration.
- Participation in the integration of company products Sentinel/Outbreak Management System (OMS) with Web Services and UI forms adaptations.
- Usage of JMeter for load and performance testing. This allowed to test and stress the application against different environments and with large amount of users Tools Used: SQL Server 2005, Java, J2EE/Apache Struts, Eclipse, Tomcat App Server, Tortoise SVN, JMeter, SOAP UI, Junit, JIRA.

Sep 2007 - Oct 2008

Softtek - GE Fleet Services

- Java/Sun IDM Developer: I was the Project Coordinator for the Maintenance Supplier Portal IDM (Sun Identity Management System). Responsible for tracking defects with all developers/testers thru Mercury Quality Center, as well as Identifying & assigning defects to developers reporting directly to the Operations Leader.
- Project Coordinator/Developer for the MySupplier IDM implementation project. Adapting the Self-Service Portal functionalities to work with a defined application, managing its requests for roles assignment over IDM System using workflows and forms.
- IDM Developer & Team Coach for all IDM implementations (MySupplier/Maintenance Supplier Fleet Projects).
- IDM Developer in the Maintenance Supplier Portal IDM implementation project. Adapting the Self-Service Portal removal and disable functionalities for roles assigned to users using IDM workflows and forms.
- Project coordinator for the Knowledge Transfer from GE Fleet headquarters at Eden Prairie, MN
- Tools used: IDM 7, IDM Business Process Editor, Oracle 9i, SQL Server 2000, Microsoft ActiveDirectory, Java, WebLogic 8, Eclipse, Linux, Tomcat, Mercury Quality Center.

Feb 2006 - Sep 2007

Softtek - GE Commercial Finance

Java/Sun IDM Developer

Nov 2003 - Jan 2006

The Brain Technologies Corp

Java Developer

Jan 2001 - Nov 2003

Zentrum Ziztemaz

Java Programmer

Education:

Bachelor's in computer science (1997) / Universidad Autonoma de Baja California.

Additional Information:

Languages: Others:

English fluent, Spanish native.

- AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification San Diego, CA Apr 2022
- Project Management Professional (PMP) Certified by PMI Dec 2017 (PMP number: 2112360)
- Scrum Master Accredited Certification Jul 2018 (Scrum-institute.org)
 Scrum Product Owner Accredited Certification Jul 2018 (Scrum-institute.org)
- Scaled Agile Framework Practitioner Certification San Diego, CA Jun 2014
- Sun Java Certified Programmer 1.4 Dec 2005